<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.github.a_issaoui.porkill</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <name>Porkill</name>
  <summary>A cyberpunk-themed GUI for monitoring and killing processes by port</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      Porkill is a Linux desktop application for visualising every open network port
      alongside the process that owns it — and killing it with one click.
    </p>
    <p>
      It reads directly from /proc/net/ with no external tools required, falling back
      to ss (JSON or legacy mode) or netstat when available. The fastest working method
      is cached automatically for subsequent refreshes.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Real-time port and process monitoring with debounced live filtering</li>
      <li>Process grouping — batch-kill all ports owned by a process in one action</li>
      <li>Container runtime detection: Docker, Podman, containerd, crun, runc, buildah</li>
      <li>Dual-mode kill: graceful SIGTERM or force SIGKILL -9, with PID-reuse safety check</li>
      <li>Privilege elevation via pkexec or sudo with a styled confirmation dialog</li>
      <li>Neon cyberpunk dark theme with semantic colour coding per protocol and state</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.github.a_issaoui.porkill.desktop</launchable>

  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>Main interface — real-time port monitor with process grouping</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/a-issaoui/porkill/master/assets/screenshot.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="2.0.3" date="2026-03-06">
      <description>
        <p>Full rewrite from Tkinter to PyQt6. Major improvements:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>QThreadPool + QRunnable worker architecture for non-blocking UI</li>
          <li>Versioned fetch-generation guard prevents stale worker side-effects</li>
          <li>Batch tree insertion for smooth rendering at 2 000+ rows</li>
          <li>lru_cache port formatter and sort key — zero per-row allocation</li>
          <li>Smart tooltip that flips above/below the hovered row</li>
          <li>os.scandir-based inode map — 2–3× faster than Path.iterdir</li>
          <li>Container runtime ancestry cache</li>
          <li>IntEnum column indices for type-safe tree access</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="2.0.0" date="2025-06-01">
      <description>
        <p>Production hardening: multi-PID group kill, PID reuse mitigation,
        debounced background filtering, and stable application lifecycle.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/a-issaoui/porkill</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/a-issaoui/porkill/issues</url>

  <developer_name>a-issaoui</developer_name>

  <provides>
    <binary>porkill</binary>
  </provides>

  <categories>
    <category>System</category>
    <category>Monitor</category>
    <category>Network</category>
  </categories>

  <keywords>
    <keyword>port</keyword>
    <keyword>process</keyword>
    <keyword>monitor</keyword>
    <keyword>kill</keyword>
    <keyword>network</keyword>
    <keyword>sysadmin</keyword>
  </keywords>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>